Vladimir Elisov

Head of Support, Engineer

Email: v.elisov@gmail.com

Phone / WhatsApp: +5511942590829

Summary

Rich experience of supporting international products and services, solving real user needs, and shaping the business's public profile from zero to hero. Open to relocation anywhere in North or South America.

Current location: Brazil.

Work Permits: Brazil, Russia, Singapore.

Working Languages: English (C2), Portuguese (B2), Russian (native).

Tech Stack: SQL, RestAPI, Atlassian Jira / Confluence / Trello, Zendesk, Red Hat Linux Server, bash scripting, Snowflake, dbt Cloud, Google Cloud, Docker / Podman, Freshdesk, HTML / CSS, Python (Pandas library), GA4.

Experience

Data Engineer

Improvado Mar 2024 - Aug 2024

Temporary contract position.

• Developed and tested SQL models for pre-built solutions aimed at visualizing marketing statistics in BI tools.

Skills used: SQL, data modeling, dbt Cloud, Google BigQuery.

Technical Writer

Lumx

Jun 2022 - Jan 2024

Lumx is a startup from Rio de Janeiro, that acts as a blockchain infrastructure provider. Contract job.

- Created English technical documentation from scratch (translated from Portuguese) for the blockchain fintech project using the Mintlify platform and maintained it for 16 months.
- Successfully provided technical support for the Sympla company during the integration of the Lumx protocol into their payment ecosystem (direct contact with company managers, explaining common error logs and server responses, escalating serious bugs to the Lumx IT department).

Skills used: MDX syntax, cURL, JS, technical writing, Mintlify, Jira, Confluence, Postman.

<u>Technical Support Engineer</u>

Mikenopa

Nov 2019 - Apr 2022

Mikenopa is an international full-service provider of guest internet and other IP networking solutions for hotel chains.

- Based on the feedback and statistics collected from customers, adjusted the SLA to shape forthcoming service enhancements and overall customer experience.
- Project managed medium scale migration of the Atlassian Server to the Cloud, successfully transitioning 52 users, 2 apps and 4 workflows in less than one month.
- Led a remote team of five customer support specialists with an average CSAT score of 90 and above.

Skills used: SQL, RHEL 7, bash, git, Atlassian suite.

Head of Support

TravelLine

Feb 2017 - Nov 2019

TravelLine is an international software company that creates PMS systems and builds websites for the hotel industry.

- As Head of Support, maintained the Problem Management Database bugtracker, ensuring all records were resolved. As part of the internal Critical Solutions Team, managed escalations and performed incident management during urgent situations.
- Working with the service stakeholders and managers created a corporate SLA for technical support and further implemented into the workflow. Developed talking scripts for L1 support.
- Created chatbots for a commercial website based on Zapier and the ChatBot framework.

Skills used: SQL, automation, QA testing, technical support, web development

Project Manager

2K-Sport May 2015 - Feb 2017

One of the largest Russian manufacturers of sports equipment.

- As part of the PM team, was responsible for creating the roadmap, directing the development and deployment of the online store for a brick-and-mortar retailer. The project was completed ahead of schedule and has remained unchanged as of 2024.
- Conducted training for employees to operate the new online sales platform.

Skills used: HTML, CSS, PHP, RHEL 7, Google Analytics, Yandex Metrica, web development

Education

Moscow Technical University of Communications and Informatics (MTUCI) Bachelor's degree, Information Technology, Engineer

Licenses & Certifications

EF SET English Certificate 79/100 (C2 Proficient)